So, in this video were are going to, by the end of it,
En este video vamos a
have written some very simple code, that is actually going to
tener escrito código muy simple, que va a
be able to say something to the screen proving
decir algo a la pantalla para probar que
that our development environment works out and that
nuestro ambiente de desarrollo funciona y
we are able to compile C++ code. So, let's get on with it!
que podemos compilar codigo en C++. ¡Vamos alla!
So, we left a couple of things downloading,
Dejamos varias descargas en proceso.
before all the chit chat, and one of those was Visual Studio. So,
antes de la charla , y una de ellas era Visual Studio.
we started Visual Studio first, and I'm hoping that it's downloaded for you now.
empezamos con Visual  STudio, espero que este ya descargado.
It depends entirely how fast your broadband is, of course.
Depende de la velocidad de tu internet.
So, here we are! I'm going to launch Visual Studio
Ya esta!. Voy a ejecutar Visual STudio por
for the fist time! Now, if you're on a Mac and you're saying, what's
primera vez! Si estas con un Mac y estás diciendo, ¿Que es
Visual Studio? What's he talking about? Well, then I'm going to cover Xcode at the end of this
Visual STudio? De qué está hablando? Bueno, cubriré también Xcode al final de este
video, again for you. So, here we go! This is the
video. ¡VAmos alla! Esta es la página web
website. We don't really need to see the website, so
No necesitamos ver la página,
there we are! Visual Studio!
aqui estamos! Visual Studio!
It's just doing some stuff, let it do some stuff OK. Let it get
Está trabajando ahora, dejemoslo trabajar.
going! Now, the flag I talked about, the Update Flag is up here. There
La bandera de la que hablaba, la de la actualización está aquí.
are five notifications. It's definitely worth doing any updates
hay cinco notificaciones. Importante actualizar todo
straight away. So, these types
Este tipo de actualizaciones
of updates, unless you recognize or are
a menos que las reconozcas o te digan
told you need to do it, you can just clear those, but if there are any major
que los necesitas, puedes eliminarlas, pero si hay alguna actualización importante
updates to the system, then you need to do that, any Visual Studio updates themselves.
en el sistema, debes hacerla. O una actualización de Visual STudio.
So, what is Visual Studio? It's an Integrated
¿Que es Visual STudio?Es un desarrollo integrado
Development Environment, it helps you write code. And this is going to be
que te ayuda a escribir código. Y va a ser un estándar en la
an industry standard tool we're using here. So, it's
industria, lo que estamos haciendo aquí,
pretty cool! It's a pretty heavy weight tool, but it's very powerful. It's very
es un poco pesado pero muy bueno.
customizable. And all we want to do here is kind of make sure that it works and
Muy personalizable. Todo lo que vamos a hacer ahora es cerciorarse de que funciona
that we can customize and we can compile.
que podamos personalizar y compilar
Compiling means turning your code into something that the computer can run. If you
compilar significa convertir tu código en algo que el ordenador pueda ejecutar.
see things like this, little errors, then the is talking about
Si ves estos pequeños errores, se refiere a que este
you being logged into your Microsoft
con sesión iniciada en tu cuenta Microsoft
Account. You don't have to do it at first, but sooner or later it's going to ask you to
No tienes porque hacerlo al principio, pero tarde o temprano te lo pedira
log into your account. So, I'm going to go ahead and
Voy a iniciar sesión ahora
do that now. And if you do see it asking you, just do sign in with
Y si te lo pregunta, inicia sesión en tu cuenta de Microsoft
the Microsoft Account, when you're first asked to do it. And once you're
en cuanto te lo pida. Cuando hayas iniciado sesión, podrás ver tu nombre aquí
signed in, you'll be able to see your name up here and the nags will go away.
y los incordios desaparecerán
So, let's go ahead and make our own new project!
Empecemos con nuestro nuevo proyecto.
Now, once we're using Unreal, then Unreal will actually create our
Por usar Unreal, Unreal creará nuestros proyectos y soluciones
projects and our solutions for us, but for now, let's get a basic familiarity
por ahora, vamos a familiarizarnos con Visual STudio
with Visual Studio. Say New Project, and then, I want you to go down
Clickeamos nuevo proyecto y vamos abajo hasta
to Visual C++, here on your list.
Visual C++ en la lista
Visual C++ and then Win32 Console
y después consola de Win32
Application. Now, where are you going to save this? Well, it's a very
¿Donde vas a guardarlo? Bueno es una aplicación muy simple
trivial application, so it doesn't really matter. I'm
por lo que da igual.
going to call it HelloWorld. What I'm saying
Voy a llamar la Hello World. Lo que digo
is that we don't really need to come back to this later. This is going to be very very simple, we're
es que no hace falta que la usemos despues.Va a ser muy muy simple
just testing that things work. So,
para probar que todo funciona. Click Amos next y Finish
just click Next and Finish. Don't worry about what any of that
No te preocupes de lo que todo esto significa
stuff means, it could take a lifetime to learn what all this means. We just need to make
puedes tirarte toda la vida aprendiendolo. Solo tenemos que asegurarnos de que
sure that our Visual Studio is going to compile C++ code, before we
Visual studio va a compilar C++, antes de instalar Unreal y prepararlo
get Unreal all setup and installed. So, here we go, this is C++!
Ok esto es C++.
So, what do we have here? At the top, we have green
Que tenemos aqui? Arriba tenemos cosas verdes
stuff that starts with a double forward slash. These are comments. They're completely
que empiezan con dobles barras oblicuas. Esto son comentarios. El ordenador los ignora
ignored by the computer. They're there to help you, and we'll be talking
completamente. Están ahí para ayudarte , y hablaremos
in the course a lot about how to use comments, but for now, we don't need anything there.
en el curso mucho acerca de cómo usar comentarios, pero por ahora no necesitamos nada ahí
#include, they allow the code to access other
#include, permite el acceso a otro código
code, in simple terms, and we are going to need one of those to make sure that
básicamente necesitaremos uno de esos para asegurarnos de que
we're able to write to the Console. And what I want you
podremos escribir en la Consola. Lo que vamos a hacer es
to do is, I want you to write #include and
escribir #include y
then, left chevron. Now, when you do that, it's going to load up a list of all the
despues, signo de menor. Cuando hagas eso, va a cargar una lista de todas las cosas
things that are available in the standard directories that Visual Studio is looking
disponibles en las carpetas estándar que Visual Studio busca.
for. And what I'm looking for is something called
y lo que buscarmos es algo llamado
&lt;iostream&gt;, i o s t r e a m. And you see how
&lt;iostream&gt;, i o s t r e a m. Y ves como
if you start typing it and then hit the Return key, it'll actually fill it in
si empiezas a escribir y presionas Enter, lo escribirá el solo.
for you. That reduces error and increases your coding speed. So,
Esto reduce errores y aumenta tu velocidad de programación.
#include &lt;iostream&gt;. That's awesome! Then, what I want you to
#include &lt;iostream&gt; EStupendo! Lo que quiero que hagas es
do is, come down to line 9 and make sure you're indented one tab.
vamos a la línea 9, y asegurate de que este un tab hacia dentro
If you do what I just did, which is select at the end of line 8 and hit Return, you
Si haces lo que acabo de hacer que es select al final de la línea 8 y presionar Enter,
will be selected in one tab, but please use a tab and not four spaces.
estara un tab hacia la derecha pero por favor usa un tab y no cuatro espacios.
So, now that we have access to &lt;iostream&gt;, within
Ahora que tenemos acceso a &lt;iostream&gt;, ahí dentro
there there's something called std, which is a name space, basically a
hay algo llamado std, que es un namespace, básicamente un
grouping of bits of code. Colon colon let's us
grupo de trozos de código. punto y coma doble nos permite
go inside that, and then, we have something called
acceder a eso, y después, tenemos algo llamado
cout. So, I want you to go std::cout space,
cout. Hacemos  std::cout space
left chevron left chevron, and we'll explain a little later in the course what
menor menor, y explicaremos después en el curso que significa esto
that means. For now, we're just trying to test that the system works,
ahora solo estamos testear que el sistema funciona,
and then, it's going to be "HelloWorld. I'm going to
despues sera Hello World. Pondré una exclamación y
put an exclamation and then a backslash n". Now look, when you write
barra inclinada n. Ahora mira, cuando escribes
code you have to be very precise. It's very important that
código debes de ser muy preciso. Es muy importante que
it looks exactly like this, and then, on the end we've got a semicolon. On the end of all
sea exactamente esto, y después, al final tenemos un punto y coma. Al final de todas la líneas
lines there's a semicolon. In fact, in C++, just like in C#, that's
hay un semicolon. De hecho, en C++ como en C#, es la unica manera
the only way the Compiler knows that your statement
que el compilador sepa que tu frase
has finished. OK! So, that's what I want you to write!
haya acabado, OK! Eso es lo que quiero que escribas!
And when you've written that, go to Debug and start with
Cuando lo hayas escrito , ve a Debug y empieza con
Debugging or Control, F, 5, and see what happens!
Debugging o Control F5, y a ver que pasa!
Would you like to build it? Yes! And look
Queremos hacer un build? SI! y mira
what pops up! A Windows Console Application
que aparece! Una aplicación de Consola de Windows
that says, "Hello World! Press any key to continue..." And when we do, it just
que dice, “Hello World!”Presiona una tecla para continuar, Y cuando lo hacemos, sale
exits. So congratulations! If you've got this far, you have your
Felicidades si has llegado hasta aquí, tienes tu
computer with an industry strength Integrated
Ordenador con un desarrollo integrado de la industria funcionando
Development Environment up and running. You're able to compile code, which means turn
puedes compilar código que significa convertir tu texto en algo que el ordenador pueda ejecutar
your text into something the computer can run ultimately, 1's
al final , en unos y ceros,
and 0's. And that is all working fantastically!
y todo funciona muy bien!
So, good job with that! You'll understand code a lot lot better
Bien hecho, entenderás el código mucho mucho mejor
as we go through the course, but you are setup and ready. We're going look at the Unreal
conforme continuemos con el curso, pero estás preparado y listo. Vamos a mirar el editor de
Editor next. And if you're on a PC, as you probably are watching this far end
Unreal después, Y si estas con un Pc
of this video, just skip the next one, it's about Xcode. See you soon!
sáltate el siguiente, es de Xcode. Hasta pronto!